Guide to the Nelva Weber papers, 1933-1986.
Weber, Nelva papers, 1933-1986.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Nelva Weber papers, 1933-1986.
4840
Nelva Margaret Weber, 1908-1990.
8.6 cubic feet; 1 map case folder; 1 box of c. 36 rolled drawings.
Correspondence, drawings, published articles, manuscripts, biographical material, photoprints and negatives, and sketches.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Correspondence, drawings, published articles, manuscripts of books and articles, biographical material, photoprints and negatives, and sketches; drawings, plans and sketches pertain to various work executed by Weber, particularly for Arrowsmith.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Landscape architect.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Correspondence; drawings and sketches; published articles and manuscripts of books and articles; biographical material; certificates and diplomas; and photographs, slides, and negatives. Drawings, plans and sketches pertain to various work executed by Weber, particularly for Arrowsmith. Slides include pictures of plants and gardens, travel views, including slides of a trip to the Galapagos, and family images. Also 3x5 cards describing varieties of plants. Illustrations to Weber's lectures on geomorphology.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Weber, Nelva Margaret, 1908-1990.
Subjects:
Landscape architecture.; Landscape architects.; Women landscape architects.
Places:
Galapagos Islands. Pictorial works.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- American Society of Landscape Architects, 1938 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Bibliography, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Climate Control (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Drainage and Irrigation, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Ecology - Prairie - Illinois, 1946-1970 (Box 1, Folder 5-6)
- Ecology - Seashore, 1939 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Environment, 1941, 1967-1973 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Estimates (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Evergreens - Broadleafed, 1962-1969 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Fences and Gates (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Garden Architecture (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Garden Calendars (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Garden Calendars - Fall (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Garden Calendars - Spring (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Garden Calendars - Summer (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Gardens - City, 1960-1973 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Gardens - Container (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Gardens - Cutting (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Gardens - History, 1971-1973 (Box 1, Folder 20-22)
- Gardens - Indoor House Plants (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Gardens - Ornaments and Furniture (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Gardens - Period and Contemporary, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Gardens - Seaside, Seaside Planting, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 26-28)
- Gardens - Wild - Native (Box 1, Folder 29)
- Gardens - Rock (Box 1, Folder 30)
- Gardens - Water (Box 1, Folder 31)
- Grading - Road Alignment - Erosion Control (Box 1, Folder 32-33)
- Horticulture Practice - Insects and Diseases (Box 1, Folder 34)
- Horticulture Practice - Maintenance, 1967-1970 (Box 1, Folder 35)
- Horticulture Practice - Planning, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 36)
- Horticulture Practice - Pruning (Box 1, Folder 37)
- Horticulture Practice - Soil Improvement - Compost, 1938 (Box 1, Folder 38)
- Landscape Architecture - History - South, 1971-1977 (Box 1, Folder 39)
- Landscape Architecture - Theory, 1934 (Box 1, Folder 40)
- Landscape Construction - Courses, 1953-1964 (Box 1, Folder 41)
- Lawns (Box 1, Folder 42)
- Lighting (Box 1, Folder 43)
- Minimum Maintenance, 1964-1971 (Box 1, Folder 44-45)
- Perennials A-B (Box 1, Folder 46)
- Perennials C-G, 1949-1957 (Box 1, Folder 47)
- Perennials - Hemoralcallis, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 48)
- Perennials I-P (Box 1, Folder 49)
- Perennials R-Z (Box 1, Folder 50)
- Perennials - General (Box 1, Folder 51)
- Planting Design - Delphinium Season (Box 1, Folder 52)
- Planting Design - Iris Season (Box 1, Folder 53)
- Planting Design - Narcissus (Box 1, Folder 54)
- Planting Design - Peony Season (Box 1, Folder 55)
- Planting Design - Phlox Season (Box 1, Folder 56)
- Planting Design - Season of Bloom (Box 1, Folder 57)
- Planting Design - Tulip Season (Box 1, Folder 58)
- Photography, 1963-1977 (Box 1, Folder 59)
- Plants - Annuals (Box 1, Folder 60)
- Plants - Bulbs - Hardy, 1957-1965 (Box 1, Folder 61)
- Plants - Bulbs - Tender (Box 1, Folder 62)
- Plants - Exotic (Box 1, Folder 63)
- Plants - Evergreens, Needled, Leaved (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Plants - Ferns (Box 2, Folder 2-3)
- Plants - Foliage Effects (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Plants - General and Trees (large shade) (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Plants - Shrubs (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Plants - Special Uses (list from book), 1949-1980 (Box 2, Folder 7-8)
- Plants - Trees (small flowering), 1970 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Plants - Vines (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Playground, Parks, Zoos, Botanical Gardens, 1958-1964 (Box 2, Folder 11-14)
- Pools, Garden Ponds, 1963-1964 (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Roses, 1952 (Box 2, Folder 16)
- Specifications - General Landscape, 1941 (Box 2, Folder 17)
- Specifications - Planting, 1941 (Box 2, Folder 18)
- Utilities, 1933 (Box 2, Folder 19)
- Walls - Slope Protection (Box 2, Folder 20)
- Mss.: The Designer in the Garden (Box 2, Folder 21-23)
- Geomorphology (Box 2, Folder 24)
- Geomorphology - Our Changeing Landscape, 1963 (Box 2, Folder 25-26)
- Lectures, 1948-1974 (Box 2, Folder 27)
- Lecture: Earth is Our Home - Natural Landscapes (Box 2, Folder 28)
- Mss.: A Little Landscape (Box 2, Folder 29-33)
- Notes on Newfoundland, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 34)
- Publicity, 1937-1974 (Box 2, Folder 35-36)
- Published Articles, 1936 (Box 2, Folder 37-39)
- Typed Articles, 1963-1978 (Box 2, Folder 40-43)
- Miscellany (Box 2, Folder 44)
- Genealogy and Family History (Box 3, Folder 1-3)
  Includes: Arrowsmith, Bane, Becker, Chamberlin, Cornell, Gwinner (Gewinner), Hatmaker, Meyer, Weber families. One letter dated 1868. Research is from about 1946-1959.
- Sammataro-Weber miscellany, 1932-1986 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Notes, Mar. 1974-Apr. 1978 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Notes, Jan. 1979-Nov. 1980 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Christmas letters, 1974-1983 (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Thesis: Prairie-Forest Borders and Their Application in Landscape Architecture, 1935 (Box 3, Folder 8)
- McLean County, Illinois (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Walnut Grove Farm and Arrowsmith, 1941-1946 (Box 3, Folder 10-12)
- Walnut Grove Farm mss. (Box 3, Folder 13-18)
- Property owned by Joseph M. Sammataro and Nelva Weber Sammataro (Box 3, Folder 19-20)
- Sammataro Records, 1975-1981 (Box 3, Folder 21-22)
- Lectures, 1966-1971 (Box 4, Folder 1-3)
- Photo - Green Garden, Old Westbury, L.I. (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Negatives - Illinois (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Photos - Sammataro miscellaneous (Box 4, Folder 6)
- Photo - Bayne coat-of-arms (Box 4, Folder 7)
- Photos - Gambrill (Box 4, Folder 8)
- Photos - "Home Place" (Box 4, Folder 9)
- Photos - Illinois [?] (Box 4, Folder 10)
- Photos - Rockford, Illinois (Box 4, Folder 11)
- Photos - Sandy and Diana Sammataro (Box 4, Folder 12)
- Photos - Nelva Weber (Box 4, Folder 13)
- Photos - for book [?] (Box 4, Folder 14-16)
- Photos - unidentified (Box 4, Folder 17)
- Sketches by Nelva Weber (Box 4, Folder 18-19)
- Photographs and Negatives (Box 5)
- Drawings: A - B (Box 6)
- Drawings: C - De F (Box 7)
- De La - Fred (Box 8)
- Frel - Hot (Box 9)
- Hou - Lit (Box 10)
- Drawings: M (Box 11)
- Drawings: N - R (Box 12)
- Drawings: Sa - Schul (Box 13)
- Drawings: Schuy - Str (Box 14)
- Drawings: Stu - Tea (Box 15)
- Drawings: Tea - Va (Box 16)
- Drawings: A - W (up to 15" x 19" drawings) (Box 20)
- Drawings: B - Go (larger than 30" drawings) (Box 21)
- Drawings: Gr - Vi (larger than 30" drawings) (Box 22)
- Drawings: Ve - Wi (Box 23)
- Drawings: We - Z (some larger than 30" drawings) (Box 24)
- Christmas Newsletters (Box 17, Folder 1)
- Book Photographs (Box 17, Folder 2-5)
- Issue of Decks for Outdoor Living (Box 17, Folder 6)
- Christmas Greetings and correspondence (Box 17, Folder 7)
- Lecture Notes by Nelva M. Weber (Box 17, Folder 8)
- Family Photographs (Box 17, Folder 9)
- Hand-written notes for Little Landscapes (Box 17, Folder 10-12)
- Newspaper Clippings (Box 17, Folder 13)
- Photographs, beach scenes and family (Box 17, Folder 14)
- Landscape Architecture Slides (Box 18)
- Watson Kamm, Minnie, Old-Time Herbs for Northern Gardens, 1938 (Box 18)
- Jekyll, Gertrude, Colour Schemes for the Flower Garden (Box 18)
- Hubbard, H.V. and Kimball, T., An Introduction to the Study of Landscape Design, 1917 (Box 18)
- Des Divers Styles de Jardins, 1914 (Box 19)
- card file on plants (Box 25)
- Nelva Weber Bachelor of Arts diploma from University of Illinois, 1934 (Box 26)
- Nelva Weber Master of Arts diploma from University of Illinois, 1935 (Box 26)
- Nelva Weber award from Illinois Wesleyan University alumni association, 1968 (Box 26)
- Plant Hardiness Zone Map, 1960 (Box 26)
- Soil Association Map of New York State, 1955 (Box 26)
- Slides of plants and gardens, travel views, and family photos, 1975-1983 (Box 27)
- Scrolls of illustrations to Weber's lectures on geomorphology, n.d. (Box 28)
- Additional material (Box 83, Folder In MS Box)
- Oversize items
  - Oversize box of ca. 36 rolls of drawings
  - Periodical - "Travels with the Soceity Fellow" and "In Memoriam: Herietta Ellery Sedgwick Lockwood" (Folder 3)
  - Perrenial Border 9' Wide X 30' Long Using Salmon Pinks (Folder 3)
  - Bird Bath and Pool for Mr. and Mrs. Harding Bancroft Place: Millbrook, NY, July 23, 1972 (Folder 4)
  - Library at Connecticut Route 25 and Longmeadow Hill Road near Williams Park (Folder 4)
  - Planting Plan for Gardens of Mr. and Mrs. Louis Marx Jr. Place: Goldens Bridge, NY, June 7, 1976 (Folder 4)
  - Planting Plan for Flower-Beds Adjacent to New Paved Terrace for Mr. and Mrs. Ernest Kanzler Place: Goose Point, Michigan, July 1947 (Folder 4)
  - Sketch of Plantings (Folder 4)
  - Plant Textures (Folder 4)
    Sketch of Plantings
  - Sketch - Yews and Junipers (Folder 4)
  - Plan - Borrowed from Nature (Folder 4)
    Sketch
  - Elevation (Folder 4)
  - Plant Forms (Folder 4)
  - Design and Layout Plan of Memorial Garden for the Rest Place: White Plains, NY, March 25, 1964 (Folder 4)
  - Planting Plan for Memorial Garden of the Rest Place: White Plains, NY, March 27, 1964 (Folder 4)
  - Landscape Plan for Property of Mrs. Edward Simmons Place: Annapolis, MD, June 1, 1977 (Folder 4)
  - Planting Plan for the Garden of Mr. and Mrs. Alfred Van Lieu Place: Providence, RI, November 16, 1977 (Folder 4)
  - Landscape Plan for Property of the Martini Families Place: Atlanta, GA, January 9, 1977 (Folder 4)
  - Preliminary Planting Plan for Property of Mr. H. Turney McKnight Place: Madonna, MD, June 2, 1975 (Folder 4)
  - Planting Plan for Garden of Mr. and Mrs. Donald Straus Place: Far Hills, NJ, August 30, 1971 (Folder 4)
  - Planting Plan for Gardens of Schuyler Mansion Place: Albany, NY, March 7, 1972 (Folder 4)
  - Preliminary Landscape Plan for Property of Dr. and Mrs. Alfred Scherzer Place: Hampton Bay, NY, October 8, 1975 (Folder 4)
  - Planting Plan for Garden of Mr. and Mrs. John Wilkie Place: Katonah, NY, October 18, 1966 (Folder 4)
  - Planting Plan for Property of Dr. and Mrs. Jorge Buxton Place: Southampton, NY, July 22, 1975 (Folder 4)
  - Flower and Vegetable Gardens for Dr. and Mrs. Jorge Buxton Place: Southampton, NY, January 22, 1977 (Folder 4)
  - Planting Plan for Pool Area of Mr. and Mrs. Ben Michaelson Place: Bridgewater, CT, August 31, 1973 (Folder 4)
  - Landscape Plan for Pool Gardens of Mr. and Mrs. Rudolf Schulhof Place: King's Point, NY, April 27, 1970 (Folder 4)
  - Planting Plan for Property of Mr. and Mrs. Harry C. Raich Place: Quogue, NY, March 2, 1973 (Folder 4)
  - Nearby Shrub Border Place: Sketch (Folder 4)
  - Detail of Entrance for the Rest Place: White Plains, NY, August 24, 1959 (Folder 4)
  - Landscape Plan for Property of the Zechiel Family Place: Cold Spring Harbor, NY, April 1, 1980 (Folder 4)
  - A Retirement House and Garden on a 10% Slope (Folder 4)
    Sketch with topography
  - Paving detail for garden terrace, detail of brick curbs, and detail of feature (Folder 4)
  - Planting Plan for Cutting Garden on the Property of Mr. William Sydeman - 1945 Place: Fishkill, NY, September 7, 1944 (Folder 5)
  - Planting Plan for the Long Border for Mrs. Clarence Alcott Place: East Hampton, NY, September 1943 (Folder 5)
  - Planting Plan for Area Around the New Paved Terrace of Mr. and Mrs. Ernest Kanzler Place: Grosse Point, MI, July 1947 (Folder 6)
  - Planting Plan for Perennial Beds for the Garden of Mr. and Mrs. Thomas L. Perkins Place: Rye, NY, July 1948 (Folder 6)
  - A Retirement House and Garden on a 10% Slope (Folder 6)
  - A Retirement House and Garden on a 10% Slope (Folder 6)
  - Mattheivs Pool Addition Place: Stonington, CT, May 20, 1977 (Folder 6)
    By Peter Kurt Woerner, Architect
  - Mattheivs Pool Addition - Elevations Place: Stonington, CT, May 20, 1977 (Folder 6)
  - Planting Plan for Flower-Beds Nearest the House of Mr. and Mrs. Ernest Kanzler Place: Grosse Point, MI, 7/1947 (Folder 7)
  - Boundary an Topography Plan for the Property of Peter and Jane Timken Matthews Place: Main Street and Grand Street in Stonington, CT, 1/1947 (Folder 7)
    By Dicsare-Bentley-Welling Enger's, Inc.
  - Planting Plan for Property of Mr. and Mrs. Andrews K. Markwald Place: Far Hills, NJ, February 3, 1977 (Folder 7)
  - Planting Plan for Quadrangle of Illinois Wesleyan University Place: Bloomington, IL, August 28, 1974 (Folder 7)
  - Terrace for Mr. and Mrs. Reginald Rose Place: Oyster Bay, NY, August 28, 1972 (Folder 8)
    8.5 X 11 Sketch
  - Terrace for Mr. and Mrs. Reginald Rose, August 28, 1972 (Folder 8)
  - Planting Plan for Garden of Mr. and Mrs. Bernard M. Shanley Place: Bernardsville, NJ (Folder 8)
  - 8.5 X 11 Sketch of East Elevation Bedroom - McKnight (Folder 8)
  - 8.5 X 11 Sketch of Parish Hall, Lawn, Garage, etc. (Folder 8)
  - Sketch of Landscape Plan for Front of Unknown House (Folder 8)
  - Landscape and Planting Plan for Property of Barbara Nyden Place: Old Lyme, CT, May 1, 1979 (Folder 8)
  - Planting Plan for Garden of Quackenbush House Place: Albany, NY, January 8, 1977 (Folder 8)
    Designed for the Fort Orange Garden Club
  - Planting Plan for Garden of Mrs. John Ottley Place: Water Town, CT, September 19, 1966 (Folder 8)
  - Cutting Border for Property of Mr. and Mrs. Rudolf Schulhoff Place: King's Point, NY, September 23, 1970 (Folder 8)
  - Landscape Suggestions for Property of Janet Stark Place: Washington Depot, CT (Folder 8)
  - Planting Plan for Flower Garden of Mr. and Mrs. Whitney Stevens Place: Southampton, NY, September 5, 1968 (Folder 8)
  - Study for Garden of Nancy Swern Place: Great Neck, NY, March 5, 1981 (Folder 8)
  - Garden for Mr. and Mrs. John Wilkie Place: Katonah, NY, April 7, 1977 (Folder 8)
  - Terrace for Mr. and Mrs. Thomas Rhine Place: Providence, RI, April 20, 1979 (Folder 8)
  - Planting Plan for Garden of Mrs. Jill Rosen Place: Scarsdale, NY, May 8, 1979 (Folder 8)
  - Alternate Scheme for Property of the Martini Families Place: Atlanta, GA, January 9, 1977 (Folder 8)
  - Planting Suggestions for Garden of Dr. and Mrs. Flint Kellogg, August 24, 1977 (Folder 8)
  - Planting Plan for Garden of Mr. and Mrs. S. Bonsal White Fox Fire Farm Place: Monkton, MD, November 18, 1976 (Folder 8)
  - Terrace for Mr. and Mrs. Reginald Rose Place: Oyster Bay, NY, August 28, 1972 (Folder 8)
  - Planting Plan for Property of Mr. and Mrs. Joseph J. Huber Jr. Place: Roslyn Heights, NY, January 7, 1976 (Folder 8)
  - Terrace for Mr. and Mrs. Reginald Rose Place: Oyster Bay, NY, August 28, 1972 (Folder 8)
  - Rhodos and Azaleas for Mrs. Richard Gambrill Place: Peapack, NJ, June 5, 1973 (Folder 8)
  - Construction Drawing for Garden of Dr. and Mrs. Alfred Scherzer Place: Hampton Bay, NY, August 26, 1975 (Folder 8)
  - Garden for Mr. and Mrs. R. B. Schulhoff Place: King's Point, NY, May 8, 1978 (Folder 8)
  - Markwald Preliminary Size Study, April 21, 1976 (Folder 8)
    Sketch of residence with topography
  - Sketch of farm house (Folder 8)
  - Little Landscape #2 (Folder 8)
  - Dressing room - south elevation - McKnight (Folder 8)
  - Dressing room - west elevation - McKnight (Folder 8)
  - Sketch of grass terrace in front of residence with row of young pine trees and stone wall (Folder 8)
  - Sketch of grass terrace in front of residence with row of young pine trees and stone wall (Folder 8)
  - Sketch of residence with entrance court, brick sitting wall, and topography (Folder 8)
  - Sketch of grass lounging area in front of bath house with a pool surrounded by gardens (Folder 8)
  - Sketch of roses on bank and auto court (Folder 8)
  - Sketch of perennials for cutting (Folder 8)
  - Sketch of small kitchen garden (Folder 8)
  - Sketch of a pool surrounded by fruit trees (Folder 8)
  - Sketch tree plantings surrounding a residence (Folder 8)
  - Small sketch of pool with summer flowering shrubs (Folder 8)
  - Edging of Iberis Sempervirens-Purity (Folder 8)
  - Planting Plan for Property of Mr. and Mrs. Theodor Swanson Place: Falls Village, CT (Folder 8)
  - Details of Wood Screen for Mr. and Mrs. Rosen Place: Scarsdale, NY, May 14, 1979 (Folder 8)
  - Landscape Plan for Property of Mr. and Mrs. Peter Matthews Place: Stonington, CT, August 23, 1978 (Folder 8)
  - Zipser Layout Plan, October 9, 1975 (Folder 8)
  - Landscape and Planting Plan for Sardana Property of Mrs. Mary C. Rockefeller Place: Bedford, NY, April 18, 1966 (Folder 9)
  - Detail of Brick Paving for Sardana Property of Mrs. Mary C. Rockefeller Place: Bedford, NY, April 17, 1966 (Folder 9)
  - Planting Plan for Garden of Mary C. Rockefeller Place: Bedford, NY, October 10, 1966 (Folder 9)
  - Planting Plan for Property of Mr. and Mrs. Gilbert Kerlin Place: Riverdale, NY, April 16, 1980 (Folder 9)
  - Sketch of residence with terrace, garage, and lawn (Folder 9)
  - Sketch of auto court (Folder 9)
  - Viburnum Border Property of Mr. and Mrs. C. D. Webster Place: Islip, NY, November 3, 1960 (Folder 9)
  - Sketch of residence with terrace and auto court (Folder 9)
  - Sketch of residence with terrace and surrounding plantings (Folder 9)
  - Zipser (Folder 9)
    Sketch of rose garden and pathways
  - Garden and Pool Area for Zeckiel Family Place: Cold Spring Harbor, NY, March 24, 1980 (Folder 9)
  - Landscape Plan for Mr. and Mrs. Emil Karkut Place: Newtown, CT, August 29, 1978 (Folder 9)
  - Layout Plan for Garden of Dr. and Mrs. Jorge Buxton Place: Southampton, NY, February 4, 1977 (Folder 9)
  - Planting Plan for Garden of Dr. and Mrs. Jorge Buxton Place: Southampton, NY, February 4, 1977 (Folder 9)
  - Pool for Dr. and Mrs. Flint Kellogg Place: S. Egermont, MA, March 10, 1980 (Folder 9)
  - Sketch of residence with garage, gym, pool, surrounding plantings, and topography (Folder 9)
  - Planting Plan for Garden of Mr. and Mrs. John Wilkie Place: Katonah, NY, October 16, 1977 (Folder 9)
  - Small sketch of circular parking area (Folder 9)
  - Courtyard Study, February 2, 1979 (Folder 9)
    Sketch of residence with paved, terrace, surrounding plantings, and garage
  - Planting Plan for the Perennial Garden of Mrs. Henry Sutphen Place: East Hampton, NY, September 18, 1944 (Folder 9)
  - Residence for Mr. and Mrs. James Porter Courtyard Study #2, April 17, 1979 (Folder 9)
  - Sketch of residence with auto court (Folder 9)
  - New Arbor for Mr. and Mrs. Timothy D. More Place: Benefit St., Providence, RI (Folder 9)
  - Fence and Gate for the Property of Mr. and Mrs. Gordan McShane Place: New Vernon, NJ, March 27, 1961 (Folder 1)
    Small Sketch 11X17
  - Fence and Gate for the Property of Mr. and Mrs. Gordan McShane Place: New Vernon, NJ, March 27, 1961 (Folder 1)
    Larger Sketch
  - Walled Garden for the Property of Mr. and Mrs. George R. Vila Place: Far Hills, NJ, April 4, 1966 (Folder 1)
  - Tool House for Mr. and Mrs. T.M. Peters Place: Claremont Road, Bernardsville, NJ, April 5, 1971 (Folder 1)
  - Tool House for Mr. and Mrs. T.M. Peters Place: Claremont Road, Bernardsville, NJ, April 9, 1971 (Folder 1)
  - Fencing of Woven Wood Saplings Laid Horizontally (Folder 1)
    On regular paper
  - Fencing of Woven Wood Saplings Laid Horizontally (Folder 1)
    On trace paper
  - Sketch of door on trace paper (Folder 1)
  - Playground Playhouse (Folder 1)
    Plan and dimensions for a playground playhouse with side and front elevations
  - Drainage and Irrigation Plan - Flushing Meadow Park Area (Folder 1)
  - Alterations to House for Amos Treat, Esq. Place: Bridgewater, CT, August 4, 1961 (Folder 1)
    Site plan with fence and rail details
  - Fencing of Woven Wood Saplings Laid Horizontally (Folder 1)
  - Planting Plan for Garden of Dr. and Mrs. Jorge Buxton Place: Westhampton, NY, February 4, 1977 (Folder 1)
  - Sketch of property site plan (Folder 1)
  - Small sketch of property site plan - Kline property(?) (Folder 1)
  - Architectural Plan for East Door in Country (Folder 1)
    Plan, elevation, and section
  - Architectural Plan for East Door in Country (Folder 1)
  - Architectural Plan for East Door in Country - Frank Fisher (Folder 1)
  - Preliminary Study for Garden of Mr. and Mrs. Alfred Van Liew Place: Providence, RI, October 20, 1977 (Folder 1)
  - Center Beds of Garden for Mr. and Mrs. Donald B. Straus Place: Far Hills, NJ, April 24, 1972 (Folder 1)
  - Plan of Arrowsmith Township, McLean County, IL Place: Arrowsmith, IL (Folder 1)
    Section line, middle of Main Street, Quarter Section Corner 46 ft. south of center line, main track of NYC & STL RR
  - Farm Plat Book and Business Guide for McLean County, IL Place: McLean County, IL (Folder 1)
  - Proposed Picnic Bench, December 4, 1941 (Folder 1)
    Plan, End View, and Elevation
  - Plan of St. George's Harbor, Rock's Harbor, and Stock's Harbor (Folder 1)
  - Curve data on trace paper (Folder 1)
  - Plan of Arrowsmith Township, McLean County, IL Place: Arrowsmith, IL (Folder 1)
  - Department of Parks - Kissena Corridor Park, Section I - Flushing Meadow Park to Kissena Park Place: Borough of Queens, NY, November 1, 1943 (Folder 2)
    Detail layout - playgournds #5 and #6, sitting areas #3 and #6
  - Gate for Mrs. Shipman (Folder 2)
  - Gate for Mrs. Shipman (Folder 2)
  - State of New York, Department of Public Works - Palisades Interstate Parkway Section 2 Place: NY (Folder 2)
    Clearance and slope diagrams showing proposed and future construction
  - Herbs for Health and Sundry Uses, 1975 (Folder 2)
    Chart prepared by D. Sammataro
  - Layout and Details for Walled Garden of Mr. and Mrs. Reuben Richards Place: Far Hills, NJ, April 5, 1962 (Folder 2)
  - Section A-A plan of a 440 yard running track and football field (Folder 2)
  - Risley Winter Garden, March 31, 1977 (Folder 2)
  - Map of McLean County, IL Place: McLean County, IL, 1904 (Folder 2)
    Parcel map with property owner names - published by F.C Hardacre, Vincennes, Ind.
  - Additional maps and plans (Folder 10-24)